System UI is one of the core applications of Android operating system with our System UI, the Android
operating system cannot really function.
So let's dig a little bit more deeper into system UI and its associated modules.
What sets of stimuli?
So System UI refers to any element displayed on the screen that is not part of an application, so any
UI element?
It is not part of a standard Android application belongs to a system you like.
So, for example, the status bar, which you see at the top or at the navigation bar, which you see
at the bottom.
Let's have a look at the U.S. system UI components.
So the status bar, the all belongs to a system.
You are the navigation bar at the bottom system you are the key guard lock screen comes after an Android
is boot up and before the launch.
That's the that's part of System UI.
And then the Power UI screen, which shows the power information like System UI and a recent screen
where you have the recent applications.
And then William UI, where you can adjust the volume, then the stack divide.
This is the split screen divide.
It's again part of System UI and up UI, which is basically an overlay like, for example, a video
overlay on top of another video that's called as UI.
So that's again implemented as part of System UI.
Then the screenshot interface belongs to System UI and the ringtone player.
These all are actually different components of System UI, so now let's open up an emulator and have
a look at some of these modules.
This is the as a part, but you have the time and other can information, and here you have got the
battery range and Wi-Fi.
So this is the settings part and the navigation bar is what you see at the bottom.
So here you have the back button, the home button and a recent application button.
And then the key guard is the screen, which you see when you switch on the phone.
This one here you swipe and it opens to launch.
So in that regard, you could configure different security mechanisms like you can have a password,
but you can have a pin code or a pattern, for example.
And then the recent screen.
Is this one so currently I don't have any recent item if you open this one, for example.
And maybe this one, this happened.
I know I have the messaging app and grown up in the recent eye.
So this belongs to system you.
And in the volume UI is nothing but this one.
So where you can increase the volume and if you click here, you get the details.
So the media volume all William Ellington, William and Allen William.
OK.
And then you have got them stacked divider.
This is basically the split screen of when I open the recent item.
If I click here, I can go to the split screen.
So in the split screen, we can divide the screen into two parts where you can have one up at the top
and another app at the bottom.
So the split screen divide, this is again implemented as part of stimuli.